Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Burt Manning Papers, 1956-1988
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- New Business Files, 1973-1986 and undated, (2 boxes)
  - Coldwell Banker, 1983-1985, (2 folders) (Box 44)
  - Creative staff experience by product category, undated (Box 44)
  - Mastercard, 1984 (Box 44)
  - McDonald's, 1975-1976 (Box 44)
  - Miscellaneous notes, undated, (2 folders) (Box 44)
  - New business campaign, JWT Copenhagen, 1973 (Box 44)
  - New business report, 1985 (Box 44)
  - Presentations on new business processes, 1979-1986 (Box 44)
  - RJR/Philip Morris, 1987 (Box 45)
  - Schlitz, 1978, (3 folders) (Box 45)
  - Six Flags, 1984 (Box 45)
  - Unnamed client, corporate name development, 1977 (Box 45)
- Writings and Speeches, 1956-1988 and undated, 4 boxes)
  - 1986 Review (Joe O'Donnell), 1986 (Box 45)
  - Advertising Planning, 1972, 1977 and undated, (2 folders) (Box 45)
  - An Agency Looks at Direct Mail (Dan Seymour), 1968 (Box 45)
  - ANA (Association of National Advertisers) speech, 1986, (2 folders) (Box 45)
  - ARF (Advertising Research Foundation) speech, 1979 (Box 45)
  - Atlanta Ad Club, 1985 (Box 45)
  - Baby Boom Generation: Fact or Fiction?, undated (Box 45)
  - Beer speech, circa 1977 (Box 45)
  - Burke Copy Research, 1973 (Box 45)
  - China presentation, 1985 (Box 45)
  - Consumerism at the Crossroads (Sentry Insurance), circa 1977 (Box 46)
  - Consumerism notes, undated (Box 46)
  - Copy Testing: For What? For Whom? (Shirley Young), 1977 (Box 46)
  - Creative presentation materials, undated (Box 46)
  - Don't Tell ME the Risks of Smoking, 1975 (Box 46)
  - Draft position paper on cigarette advertising, undated (Box 46)
  - Executive interview, 1976 (Box 46)
  - Experimental Research on the Effects of TV Clutter (Michael Ray and Peter Webb), 1976 (Box 46)
  - Flippers--Changes in the Way Americans Watch TV, undated (Box 46)
  - Forget the Product Life Cycle Concept! (Nariman Dhalla and Sonia Yuspeh), 1976 (Box 46)
  - Gadfly (George Orwell, Why I Write; Saul Bellow, Deep Readers of the World Beware!), 1959 May-June (Box 46)
  - Great Expectations (Arnold Grisman), 1978 (Box 46)
  - Group dynamics, notes, 1971-1974 and undated (Box 46)
  - How a Creative Man Uses Research to Sell, undated (Box 46)
  - How Advertising Works (Grey Advertising), 1968 (Box 46)
  - How to Create Good Advertising (David Ogilvy), typescript, 1956 (Box 46)
  - How to Get a Better Return on Your Advertising Investment (Charlotte Beers), 1974 (Box 46)
  - How to Get Research Thinking into the Creative Act, 1975 (Box 46)
  - How to Get the Best from Your Advertising Agency (Robin Restall), 1985 (Box 46)
  - Ideas and Ideals: A Farewell Memorandum from Arthur E. Tatham, 1973 (Box 46)
  - Inspiration and Perspiration, undated (Box 46)
  - It Doesn't Take an Ugly Goose to Lay a Golden Egg (James Jordan), 1976 (Box 46)
  - J. Walter Thompson USA, Super Bowl XIX and the Million Dollar Minute, 1985 (Box 46)
  - JWT Chicago Review System, 1966 (Box 46)
  - Key Financial Problems in Advertiser-Agency Relationships (Phillip Schaff), 1963 (Box 46)
  - Leadership at JWT, 1978 (Box 46)
  - Life Study of Psychographics (Alan Nelson), 1969 (Box 46)
  - Love Times, 1976 (Box 46)
  - Media Report: Advertising and Spanish Speaking Americans, 1974 (Box 47)
  - Media Report: Primetime Network Television Schedule, 1974 (Box 47)
  - Memo re Roper Report 78-3 (Rena Bartos), 1973 (Box 47)
  - North American Seminar, 1975 (Box 47)
  - Observations on Australian Advertising (Don Robertson), 1978 (Box 47)
  - On the Difference Between Taking One's Work Seriously, and Taking Oneself Seriously (Andrew Kershaw), 1976 (Box 47)
  - Our Creative Disciplines, undated (Box 47)
  - Presentation drafts and notes, 1976-1977 and undated, (4 folders) (Box 47)
  - Presentation to Tom Wyman, CBS, 1980 (Box 47)
  - Problems of the Creative Department, undated (Box 47)
  - Product Life Cycle notes, undated (Box 47)
  - Professional Crimes at JWT (Robert Sturtevant), 1975 (Box 47)
  - Professional Development at J. Walter Thompson, 1985 (Box 47)
  - Protective Services Market, undated (Box 47)
  - Ralph Nader's Magnificent Fallacy, undated (Box 47)
  - Red Cross, 1976 (Box 47)
  - Remarks by Granger Tripp, 1977 (Box 47)
  - Remarks on Regulation of Advertising Sweetened Products to Children (Kenneth Mason, Quaker Oats Company), undated (Box 47)
  - Reshaping JWT for Future Needs and Opportunities, 1978 (Box 47)
  - Roots--Communication, 1981 (Box 47)
  - Standard Brands Marketing Seminar: Getting Better Advertising, Developing Brand Advertising (Stuart Shaw), 1978 (Box 47)
  - Stimulus and Response, 1975 (Box 47)
  - Stimulus and Response (JWT Flagship articles by Bill Siebert, Terry Boyle, Donald Evanson, Bella Manalo), 1975 (Box 47)
  - The 1980s: An Advertising Perspective, 1981 (Box 47)
  - The Advertising Development Process, undated (Box 47)
  - The American Consumer: Myth and Reality, 1977 (Box 47)
  - The Business of Acquiring New Business, undated (Box 47)
  - The Consumer's New Reality (Joel Baumwoll), 1976 (Box 48)
  - The Effect of Current and Future Economic Development on Advertising and Marketing, 1974 (Box 48)
  - The New American Consumer, 1985-1987, (4 folders) (Box 48)
  - The New Media, 1980 (Box 48)
  - The Thompson Edge, layout draft, undated (Box 48)
  - The U.S. Multinational Advertising Agency and Public Policy (Arnold Weinstein), 1977 (Box 48)
  - The Uses and Abuses of Survey Research in Advertising Regulation (Joel Baumwoll), 1976 (Box 48)
  - The Uses of Ideology for Environmental Analysis (G.C. Lodge), undated (Box 48)
  - To the Organization, From John O'Toole, 1976 (Box 48)
  - Trends in American Advertising (Don Johnston), 1980 (Box 48)
  - Trends in the Cost of Advertising Messages (Robert Coen, McCann Erickson), undated (Box 48)
  - Trends in U.S. Advertising, 1980 (Box 48)
  - Under New Management (Jwt publication), undated (Box 48)
  - Untitled speech, 1976 and undated, (2 folders) (Box 48)
  - Untitled speech on creativity, circa 1988 (Box 48)
  - Welcome to Fort Lauderdale (Unique Maps), undated (Box 48)
  - What is a Good Magazine Ad? (Jack Cronin), 1974 (Box 48)
  - What JWT Stands For, undated (Box 48)
  - What's It Like for a Creative Person at JWT?, draft, undated (Box 48)
  - Where JWT Stands Today, undated (Box 48)
- Audiovisual Materials
  - Carr Capabilities presentation. 1986. Umatic. (Box AV1)
  - Untitled. No. 1, Burt and Jack P., 9 am-10am. 1985 Nov. 12. Audio cassette. (Box AV1)
  - Untitled. No. 2, 3, 11 am-12 pm. 1985 Nov. 12. Audio cassette. (Box AV1)
  - Untitled. No. 4, 5, 1:30 pm-4 pm. 1985 Nov. 12. Audio cassette. (Box AV1)
  - Untitled. No. 6, 4 pm-6:30 pm. 1985 Nov. 12. Audio cassette. (Box AV1)
- Oversized Materials
  - Gravy Master, 1974 (Box OV1)
  - Quaker Oats, Puss 'n Boots Flavor Morsels, plus articles on cats, 1973 and undated (Box OV1)
  - STP Corporation, storyboards, circa 1975 (Box OV1)
  - Cartoon: All Those Opposed, Signify By Saying I Quit (Van), undated (Box OV2)
  - GTE Sprint, storyboards, 1986 (Box OV2)
  - Miller Brewing, How People Choose Between Brands of Beer, transparencies, undated (Box OV2)
  - Various accounts, Direct Margin Report, 1984 (Box OV2)
- Restricted Materials
  - Personnel-related correspondence [Closed until 2027.], 1984-1987 (Box R1)